## Mahdieh Zabihimayvan

## Curriculum Vitae

Phone: (937) 775-5217 Email: Zabihimayvan.2@wright.edu,

Home page: http://knoesis.org/mahdieh mahdieh@knoesis.org

Current Location: Dayton, Ohio, USA

### **Personal Statement**

I am a PhD student of computer science and a graduate research assistant working on deep learning and anomaly detection. Through several theoretical and applied projects, I have explored various concepts from computer networks and web programming to machine learning techniques. I am fascinated with using machine learning and soft computing techniques in anomaly detection for different fields such as web traffic detection and defect detection in physical objects.

#### Education

#### Ph.D., Computer Science (GPA:4.0)

2017-Present Wright State University, Dept. of Computer Science and Engineering, Dayton, Ohio, USA

Advisor: Dr. Derek Doran

Focus: Machine learning, soft computing, data characterization, anomaly detection, statistical analysis, high-performance computing

#### M.S., Computer Engineering-Software (GPA:4.0)

2012-2014

Imam Reza International University, Dept. of Computer and Information Technology, Iran

Advisor: Dr. Majid Vafaei Jahan

Thesis: A Proposed Algorithm Based on Markov Clustering for Web Robot Detection Focus: Evolutionary computation and optimization methods, machine learning, soft computing, data mining

#### B.S., Computer Engineering-Software

Ferdowsi University, Dept. of Computer Engineering, Iran

Advisor: Dr. Mohsen Kahani

Thesis: Designing and Implementing a Web-based Account Framework Focus: Computer networks, web programming, database design development

# **Research Experience**

#### Wright State University, Dayton, Ohio, USA

Graduate Research Assistant, Dept. of Computer Science & Engineering

Advisor: Dr. Derek Doran

• Soft computing and machine learning techniques in anomaly detection with focus on web traffic detection (MATLAB and Python)

- Statistical Analysis and machine learning models in web session characterization (Python)
- High-performance computing (Python)

2007-2011

2017-Present

### Imam Reza International University, Mashhad, Iran

2014-2016

Department of Computer and Information Technology

Advisor: Dr. Majid Vafaei Jahan

- Dynamic feature selection based on Fuzzy Rough Set theory (MATLAB)
- Soft computing techniques in web session detection (MATLAB)
- Markov processes with focus on Markov Clustering algorithm (MATLAB)
- Using Fuzzy Inference System based on decision trees as web visitor classification (MATLAB)
- Evolutionary computing techniques as web traffic classifiers (MATLAB)
- Data mining techniques in processing data (Weka, MATLAB)

## Ferdowsi University, Iran

2011-2012

Information and Communication Center, Network & Web developing Group

- Web programming (PHP, CSS, JavaScript, HTML)
- Network management and Security

## Mashhad University of Medical Science (MUMS), Iran

2009

Information Technology Center, Web Designing Group

- Web programming (CSS, HTML) and designing websites
- Working with content management systems based on Microsoft SharePoint

## **Teaching Experience**

#### Imam Reza International University, Iran

Graduate Teaching Assistant, Dept. of Computer and Information Technology

2012-2014

- Teaching Assistant of data mining for M.S. Students
  - o Teaching data mining tools in MATLAB and Weka
- Teaching Assistant of advanced engineering mathematics in software engineering for M.S. Students
  - o Statistical analysis and tests, random number generations, finite Markov chain and its algorithmic application
- Teaching Assistant of computer performance evaluation and modeling for M.S. Students
  - o Queueing networks and Markov chains, Markov processes for stochastic modeling, test functions for optimization needs, Fuzzy control of queueing system, hidden Markov model
- Algorithm design for B.S. students
  - o Time complexity of algorithms, recursion equations, sort algorithms, dynamic programming

# **Technical Qualifications**

Database Programming: Microsoft SQL Server, MySQL, Microsoft Access Programming Language: Python, MATLAB, Java, C, PHP, CSS, HTML

Data Mining Tools: MATLAB, WEKA

## **Selected Publications**

- M. Zabihimayvan, D. Doran (2018), "Some (Non-)Universal Features of Web Robot Traffic," 52th Annual Conference on Information Sciences and Systems (CISS), IEEE, Princeton University, NJ, US, (Accepted).
- M. Zabihimayvan, R. Sadeghi, N. Rude, D. Doran (2017), "A Soft Computing Approach for Benign and Malicious Web Robot Detection," Expert Systems with applications, 87, 129-140, (Impact factor: 3.928).
- J. Hamidzadeh, M. Zabihimayvan, R. Sadeghi (2017), "Detection of Web site visitors based on fuzzy rough sets," Soft Computing, In Press, (Impact factor: 2.472).
- M. Zabihimayvan, M. Vafaei Jahan, J. Hamidzadeh (2014), "A Density Based Clustering Approach for Web Robot Detection," The 4th International IEEE conference on Computer and knowledge Engineering, IEEE, (Accept Rate: 22%).
- M. Zabihimayvan, M. Vafaei Jahan, J. Hamidzadeh (2014), "A density based clustering approach to distinguish between web robot and human requests to a web server," The ISC International Journal of Information Security, 6(1), 77-89.
- M. Zabihimayvan, M. Vafaei Jahan, J. Hamidzadeh (2014), "Fuzzy Inference for Intrusion Detection of Web Robots in Computer Networks," 45th Annual Iranian Mathematics Conference, In Persian.
- M. Zabihimayvan, M. Vafaei Jahan (2014), "An Optimum Markov Clustering Algorithm for Accurate Web Robots Detection," The 7th International Conference of Iranian Operations Research Society, In Persian.
- M. Zabihimayvan, M. Vafaei Jahan (2013), "Web Robot Detection with Fuzzy Inference System Based on Decision Trees," The Seventh International Iranian Data Mining Conference, In Persian.

### **Honors and Awards**

• Awarded a fully paid travel to attend CRA-W Grad Cohort for Women 2018, San Francisco, CA	2018
Dept. of Computer Science and Engineering, Wright State University	
• Top researcher of M.Sc. students of Software Engineering	2017
Dept. of Computer and Information Technology, International University of Imam Reza	
• Awarded from Vice Chancellor of Research and Technology for publishing the paper "Detection	2016
of Web site visitors based on fuzzy rough sets"	
Dept. of Computer and Information Technology, International University of Imam Reza	
• Ranked 2nd in the academic period among the students matriculated from 2012 to 2014	2014
Dept. of Computer and Information Technology, International University of Imam Reza	
• Ranked 2nd among participants in <i>Nationwide</i> Azad Universities Entrance Exam for graduate studies	2011
	2006
• Ranked Top 1% among over 300,000 participants in <i>nationwide</i> universities entrance exam for undergraduate studies	2000

#### Service

2017 Journal Referee:

Computers and Security